#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rachitiitr (LinkedIn) rachitiitr.blogspot.in/ (Blog) youtube.com/c/RachitJain (Personal) rachitiitr.com (Personal)

## Top Skills

C++

**JavaScript** 

**Data Structures** 

### Languages

Hindi

**English** 

Marathi

# Rachit Jain

FullStack SDE-3 | ex-Microsoft | Programming YouTuber (7.5 million views)

Gurugram

# Summary

YouTube Channel: https://youtube.com/rachitjain

YouTube Channel in Hindi: https://www.youtube.com/channel/

UCmqetLRGYFcu-mU9DONrDTw

Twitter: https://twitter.com/rachitiitr

Instagram: https://instagram.com/rachitiitr Discord: https://discord.gg/qSkVbZk6NR

Github: https://github.com/rachitiitr

Personal Portfolio Website: https://rachitiitr.com

A FullStack Developer who has \*professional\* work experience with

Frontend - React, React Hooks, Redux, JavaScript (ofcourse), CSS/ SCSS

Backend - Django, NodeJS, Express, C++, C#

Testing - Jest (for JavaScript), React Testing Library (RTL)

Cloud - Microsoft Azure

Dev Tools - Strong with Bash Scripting, Git

Web Server - Nginx

Data Analytics - Pandas (Python), ELK (Elastic Search, Logstash,

Kibana), Grafana, Prometheus

Other than that, I have also made Android Apps on Playstore with 1000+ installs and 4.3+ rating.

Few things that make me stand out of the crowd -

- 0. I have explored a plethora of technology stack in my professional career
- I am a very fast learner \*
- 2. I am used to working on new codebases with minimal KT / supervision
- 3. I am highly enthusiastic and self-motivating programmer

- 4. I am a good mentor and successful in running a 140k+ subscribed YouTube channel
- 5. I have given tech talks, workshops and judged Hackathons in various Indian colleges including IIITH, NIT Raipur, NIT Silchar, NIT Ranchi, and counting!
- 6. You can find my Open Source work on Github (2.3k followers and repos with 1.1k+ stars)
- 7. I am always hungry for learning and improving as a person
- 8. My communication skills are fluent and generate clarity
- 9. I have quick turnaround time for the feedback I receive (as told by my managers)
- \* Developed this skills in IIT Roorkee where I scored a ~9.0 CGPA in Electrical Engineering as well as became the top rated programmer from IIT Roorkee 2017 batch(including students from Computer Science branch) on Competitive Programming websites like Codeforces and Codechef)

# Experience

Tower Research Capital
2 years 4 months
Software Developer III
January 2021 - Present (6 months)

Software Developer II

March 2019 - December 2020 (1 year 10 months)

Microsoft Software Developer June 2017 - February 2019 (1 year 9 months) Hyderabad Area, India

Working in the Architecture team to create re-usable components for other developers and building packages to handle cross-cutting concerns and empowering developers to focus on business logic.

Working on designing the Cloud Architecture of the apps, building scalable microservices and triggering alerts using proper telemetry logging.

Information Management Group, IIT Roorkee Android Lead

January 2014 - May 2017 (3 years 5 months)

Mentored juniors.

Developed android apps.

Flipkart

Summer Intern

May 2016 - July 2016 (3 months)

Bangalore

Designed and developed Subscription Service for Flipkart from scratch.

#### Grofers

Summer Intern

May 2015 - July 2015 (3 months)

- \*Android App Development
- My work for Animated Onboarding to the Grofers App (10 million+ installs) went into Production
- Leaded the Grofers Delivery Partner app and did speed optimisations via changing the layout structure
- Worked on GCM, Data Handling (send/receive json, images, files)
- Coded new screens / views.

## Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Electrical Engineering · (2013 - 2017)

**DAV Public School** 

· (2009 - 2012)